Preliminary Inventory to the Jürgen Perduss Collection, 1987-1995.
Hoover Institution Archives
Jürgen Perduss Collection,
1987-1995.
94037
Perduss, Jürgen, collector.
5 manuscript boxes (2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Computer disks, lists, reports, roster, telephone directory, code book, judicial decision, and printed matter, relating to the organizational structure and operations of the East German secret service, and to post-unification investigations of it. Includes lists of East German secret service agents or informants, with identifying code numbers and payments received.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1994
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Secret service--Germany (East); Germany (East) Ministerium für Staatssicherheit.; Germany.
Container List
- Urteil des Bundesverfassungsgerichts zur Agententätigkeit, 1995. Typescript (Box 1.)
- "Der Prozess gegen Markus Wolf." Zusammenfassung der Rechtsanwälte, Schlusswort von Markus Wolf, Plädoyers der Rechtsanwälte [...], und Erklärung von Markus Wolf, 1993. Photocopy of typescript and clippings
- Insiderkomitee zur Aufarbeitung der Geschichte des MfS e.V., "Das Politische Wirken der Kirchen in der DDR und die Reaktionen des MfS," Berlin 1993. Typescript and brochure
- Fernsprechverzeichnis des MfS [no names, just by title]
- Vorläufiger Diensteinheitenschlüssel des MfS, 1987
- Die Struktur des Ministeriums für Staatssicherheit [with names]
- "Geheimdienste in Deutschland nach 1945. Anhörung der Alternativen-Enquete-Kommission 15. Dezember 1993 in Berlin." Special issue of IK-KORR, published by the Insider-Komitee zur Aufarbeitung der Geschichte des MfS
- Short list of names in alphabetical order (Box 2.)
- List of names sorted by PKZ (Box 2-4.)
- Twenty-four floppy disks (Box 5.)
- Vorläufiger Diensteinheitenschlüssel des MfS. See also Box 1
- Aufstellung der an der Juristischen Hochschule Potsdam durchgführten Promotionsverfahren. List of names with topics, dates, and grades